# Prakhar Ganesh

COMPUTER SCIENCE · PHD STUDENT

McGill University | Quebec Al Institute (Mila)

Research Interests: I am interested in the challenges that arise in machine learning when moving from the sandbox to the real world, primarily at the intersection of various pillars in trustworthy machine learning, including fairness, privacy, adversarial robustness, model compression, etc., focusing on uncovering the learning dynamics of neural networks.

# **Education**

# McGill University | Quebec AI Institute (Mila)

PHD COMPUTER SCIENCE (THESIS) | ADVISOR: PROF GOLNOOSH FARNADI

Jan 2024 - Present

#### **National University of Singapore (NUS)**

MASTER OF COMPUTING (AI SPECIALISATION) | ADVISOR: PROF REZA SHOKRI

Aug 2021 - Mar 2023

#### Indian Institute of Technology Delhi (IITD)

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Aug 2015 - May 2019

# Work Experience \_

NATIONAL UNIVERSITY OF SINGAPORE (NUS) | RESEARCH INTERN ALVISUAL | AI ENGINEER (INTERN) ADVANCED DIGITAL SCIENCES CENTER (ADSC) | RESEARCH ENGINEER

Jan 2023 - Apr 2023 Jan 2022 - Mar 2022

Jun 2019 - July 2021 Jan 2019 - May 2019

WEALTHNET ADVISORS | ANALYST (INTERN)

May 2018 - July 2018

# **Publications**

KRIDA.AI | ENGINEER (INTERN)

## An Empirical Investigation into Benchmarking Model Multiplicity for Trustworthy Machine Learning

IEEE/CVF WINTER CONFERENCE ON APPLICATIONS OF COMPUTER VISION (WACV), 2024

**Prakhar Ganesh** 

## On The Impact of Machine Learning Randomness on Group Fairness

[BEST PAPER AWARD] ACM CONFERENCE ON FAIRNESS, ACCOUNTABILITY AND TRANSPARENCY (FACCT), 2023 Prakhar Ganesh, Hongyan Chang, Martin Strobel, Reza Shokri

#### YOLO-ReT: Towards High Accuracy Real-time Object Detection on Edge GPUs

IEEE/CVF WINTER CONFERENCE ON APPLICATIONS OF COMPUTER VISION (WACV), 2022

Prakhar Ganesh, Yao Chen, Yin Yang, Deming Chen, Marianne Winslett

#### HiKonv: High Throughput Quantized Convolution With Novel Bit-wise Management and Computation

ASIA AND SOUTH PACIFIC DESIGN AUTOMATION CONFERENCE (ASP-DAC), 2022

Yao Chen, Xinheng Liu, Prakhar Ganesh, Junhao Pan, Jinjun Xiong, Deming Chen

# Compressing Large-Scale Transformer-Based Models: A Case Study on BERT

TRANSACTIONS OF THE ASSOCIATION FOR COMPUTATIONAL LINGUISTICS (TACL), 2021

Prakhar Ganesh, Yao Chen, Xin Lou, Mohd. Ali Khan, Yin Yang, Hassan Sajjad, Preslav Nakov, Deming Chen, Marianne Winslett

# Learning-based Detection and Characterization of Time Delay Attack in Cyber-Physical Systems

IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON SMART GRID (TSG), 2021

Prakhar Ganesh, Xin Lou, Yao Chen, Rui Tan, David K.Y. Yau, Deming Chen, Marianne Winslett

#### Assessing and Mitigating the Impact of Time Delay Attack: Case Studies for Power Grid Controls

IEEE JOURNAL ON SELECTED AREAS IN COMMUNICATIONS (JSAC), 2020

Xin Lou, Cuong Tran, Rui Tan, David K.Y. Yau, Zbigniew T. Kalbarczyk, Ambarish Kumar Banerjee, Prakhar Ganesh

# **Awards and Scholarships**

- 2024 Graduate Excellence Award, McGill University
- **Graduate Scholarship**, Prof. Golnoosh Farnadi, Quebec Al Institute (Mila) 2023
- 2023 UdeM Exemption Grant, University of Montréal
- Best Paper Award, ACM Conference on Fairness, Accountability and Transparency (FAccT) 2023
- 2023 Travel Grant, ACM Conference on Fairness, Accountability and Transparency (FAccT)
- 2022 Winner, 8-Bit Bias Bounty Competition - Supervised Learning Track
- 2021 Top 3 Teams, ASP-DAC System Design Contest

# **Preprints/Manuscripts**

#### Free Lunch for Co-Saliency Detection: Context Adjustment

ARXIV PREPRINT ARXIV:2108.02093

Lingdong Kong, Prakhar Ganesh, Tan Wang, Junhao Liu, Le Zhang, Yao Chen

# Restructuring Conversations using Discourse Relations for Zero-shot Abstractive Dialogue Summarization

ARXIV PREPRINT ARXIV:1902.01615

Prakhar Ganesh, Saket Dingliwal

### VLSTM: Very Long Short-Term Memory Networks for High-Frequency Trading

ARXIV PREPRINT ARXIV:1809.01506

Prakhar Ganesh, Puneet Rakheja

### Nucl2Vec: Local alignment of DNA sequences using Distributed Vector Representation

**BIORXIV PREPRINT DOI:10.1101/401851** 

Prakhar Ganesh, Gaurav Gupta, Shubhi Saini, Kolin Paul

# **Professional Service**

2024	Peer Reviewer.	ACL Rolling Review (A	(RR
------	----------------	-----------------------	-----

- 2024 **Program Committee (PC) Member**, ACM Conference on Fairness, Accountability and Transparency (FAccT)
- 2024 **Peer Reviewer**, Winter Conference on Application of Computer Vision (WACV)
- 2023 Peer Reviewer, Algorithmic Fairness through the lens of Time (AFT) Workshop, NeurIPS
- 2023 **Ethics Reviewer**, Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS)
- 2023 **Peer Reviewer**, Al Communications
- 2022 **Peer Reviewer**, Winter Conference on Application of Computer Vision (WACV)
- 2021 **Peer Reviewer**, AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI)
- 2021 **Peer Reviewer**, Winter Conference on Application of Computer Vision (WACV)
- 2020 **Peer Reviewer**, Computer Speech and Language
- 2020 **Peer Reviewer**, Signal, Image and Video Processing